

Michał Wylegała

- Zurich, Switzerland
- +48 883 015 158
- +41 798 247 558
- wylegala.michall@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I am Polish, I am 26, I am a technical person and I already have 6 years of professional experience. Since I remember, I was interested in a career in IT and getting to know the magic that happens behind the scenes. I have spent the last 3 years as an interface between the worlds of business and IT engineering helping everyone understand how that magic works and automates customer experience in the healthcare industry. My main responsibilities for the past 3 years were acting as a technical delivery lead and managing the entire engineering process for marketing automation and analytics projects. I am a perfectionist with an analytical mind. I value a good atmosphere at work, I have empathy for others, and I am a goal-oriented leader, so I am not afraid to roll up my sleeves and get to work. In my 6 years at GSK, I was considered a high performer twice and promoted through talent appointment. I would like to continue my career in Switzerland in a company that will appreciate my skills and development potential. Recently I moved to Zurich and I'm working remotely for a polish company, but I am looking for job opportunities in Switzerland.

Soft skills

- Email marketing
- Tech lead
- People management
- Customer experience
- Project management
- Data Driven marketing
- Stakeholder management

Technical skills

- Salesforce Marketing Cloud
- Adobe Experience Cloud (Analytics, Campaign, Target, AEM)
- Veeva CRM
- Tealium CDP
- 3rd party tags and cookie banners via Tealium, GTM and Ensighten
- Campaign effectiveness tracking with Claravine codes
- Azure micro-services & data lake

Work History

08.2021 - Current

Principal Engineer in Marketing Automation

GSK - Poznań, Poland

- Managing digital engineering process in a team of 20 people working on social media, email marketing, data analytics and measurement
- Coordination of digital projects with internal and outsourced resources
- Ownership of marketing automation strategy
- Ownership of digital marketing platforms and vendor relationship
- Creation and technical ownership of a Data Driven Customer experience catalogue in a 100+ market model
- Service management for requests and incidents

05.2020 - 08.2021

Manager in Digital Marketing Engineering

GSK - Poznań, Poland

- Managing a team of 6 direct reports
- Talent management
- Development planning
- Product design and shaping email marketing roadmap
- Creation of Data Driven Customer Experience program
- Improving engineering standards for quality and the best delivery time

08.2019 - 05.2020

Tech Subject Matter Expert in Campaign Automation

GSK - Poznań, Poland

- Translating business problems into technical requirements
- Developing system architecture and creating solution designs
- Enhancing customer profile with a use of CDP platform
- Defining KPIs for campaign effectiveness tracking
- Orchestrating data & building re-targeting models
- Creating and running marketing automation user journeys

04.2018 - 08.2019

Digital Marketing Tech Consultant

GSK - Poznań, Poland

- Content Authoring of GSKpro.com portal
- 3rd party tagging & cookie banners
- Creating programmatic ads to support product launches
- Building personalized content offers and a/b testing campaigns

04.2017 - 04.2018

Digital Marketing Tech Specialist

GSK - Poznań, Poland

- Content Authoring of GSK Pro websites
- A/B testing
- Configuration of on-site analytics with Adobe Analytics

11.2016 - 04.2017

Digital Marketing IT Specialist

IT Kontrakt - Poznań, Poland

Complementary worker for GSK.

- Content Authoring of GSKpro.com for Belgian market
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Education

01.2021 -07.2022

Master of Management Degree in IT Manager, Management, WSB Schools of Banking - Poznań, Poland

- Strategic management
- Managing innovation
- Finance management
- Business models
- Marketing strategies
- Managing change
- IT project management

10.2017 -01.2021

Bachelor of Engineering Degree in E-commerce, Computer Science, WSB Schools of Banking - Poznań, Poland

- Digital marketing
- Agile project management
- C# object-oriented programming
- Web apps development
- Social media
- Data base management

Courses & Certificates

- ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management issued by AXELOS,
- VFQ level 2 Agile Product Management issued by Emergn,
- Tealium CDP EventStream issued by Tealium Education,
- Tealium CDP AudienceStream issued by Tealium Education,
- Adobe Analytics course,
- Adobe Target course,
- Salesforce Marketing Cloud trainings on Trailblazers.

Hobbies

- Formula 1
- Sport (mostly bike and running)
- Board games

Languages

German: Basic Polish: Native English: Fluent

Ukrainian: Intermediate

Spanish: Basic

I am fluent in Polish and English, which I use at work daily. I studied German at school for 3 years but never used it. I set myself a goal to learn this language in 2023